Mss.Ms.Coll.97
American Philosophical Society
- III. Penobscot (Algonquian), 6.5 Linear feet (Box 15-27)
  - B. Linguistics (Box 19-23)
    - Algonquian Person Hierarchy: Morphosyntactic or Semantic, 1982; 2.0 p.; Jolley, Catherine A. (Box 21)
    - Passamaquoddy Preverbs: Examples, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Passamaquoddy Names of Living Creatures, 1981; 1.0 p.; Leland, Lloyd (Box 21)
    - Less Common Patterns of Reduplication, 1982; 1.0 p. (Box 21)
    - [Linguistic Comparisons among Algonquian Languages], n.d.; 42.0 p. (Box 21)
      Incomplete manuscript. Author unknown
    - Micmac Lexicon, 1979; 135.0 p.; Metallic, Alphonse; DeBlois, A. D. (Box 21)
    - Linguistic Classification of Powhatan, 1933; 4.0 p.; Michelson, Truman, 1879-1938 (Box 21)
      Photocopy. With note by Wes Taukchiray
    - Micmac, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Names - Background, 4.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Names of Islands in Penobscot River..., 1.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Contributions to Anthropology: Linguistics I (Algonquian), 1964; 178.0 p.; National Museum of Canada. (Box 21)
      Bulletin 214. With copious annotations by Siebert
    - Notes on Eastern Abenaki Dialects, n.d.; 2.0 p.
    - Passamaquoddy Version of Our Father, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 21)
    - Penobscot-Algonquian Roots and Reconstructions, 3.0 folders (Box 22)
      - Folder 1, n.d.; S: 82; 236.0 p. (Box 22)
      - Folder 2, n.d.; S: 83; 212.0 p. (Box 22)
      - Folder 3, n.d.; S: 84; 192.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot and Penobscot Dialect Notes, 2.0 folders (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Botany Notes, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Dialects, n.d.; 16.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Field Notes, 1937; 31.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Genealogy and Linguistic Notes, 15.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Grammar Notes, n.d.; 16.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Grammar Outline, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Lesson Plans, n.d.; 22.0 p. (Box 22)
    - Penobscot Notes, n.d.; 10.0 folders (Box 22-23)
    - Penobscot Phonemes, n.d.; 82.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Penobscot Phonemes. Note cards, n.d.; 17.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Penobscot Place Names, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Penobscot Primer, n.d.; 16.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Penobscot Vocabulary, n.d.; 3.0 folders (Box 23)
    - Proto-Algonquian [c] and [s], 3.0 p.; Pentland, David H. (Box 23)
    - Why There are no Passives in Algonquian, 1985; 3.0 p.; Piggott, G. L. (Box 23)
    - Proto-Algonkian Stems in /P-1, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Proto-Algonquian Notes, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Proto-Algonquian -- Penobscot Comparison, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 23)
    - James Rosier's List of Indian (Eastern Abenaki) Words, 1983; 25.0 p.; Quinn, Alison M.; Quinn, David B. (Box 23)
      Photocopied appendix from Quinn and Quinn (eds.), The English New England Voyages, 1602-1608 (London: Hakluyt Society, 1983)
    - Review of Bloomfield, n.d.; 14.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Some Comments on Ojibwa Ethnonotany; Algonquian Trade Language Areas (Map), 1982; 5.0 p.; Rhodes, Richard A., 1946- (Box 23)
    - Thomas Harriot (1560-1621) and the English Origins of Algonkian Linguistics, 1992; 16.0 p.; Salmon, Vivian (Box 23)
      Historiographia Linguistica vol. xix, no. 1. Photocopy
    - Two Maliseet Derivatives in Current Maine and New Brunswick Forestland Speech: Logan and Bogan, 16.0 p.; Sands, Donald B. (Box 23)
    - Dialect Symbols in Aubery's Dictionary, n.d.; 25.0 p.; Seeber, Pauleena MacDougall (Box 23)
      Two copies
    - Distinctions of Some Isomorphic Particles, Preverbs, Roots, Medials, and Enclitics in Penobscot, 1.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
      Abstract only
    - Incompatible Designata in Some Compound Verbs of Penobscot, With Preverbs of Adverse Meaning, 18.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
    - Modes of Independent Order Verbs in Eastern Abenaki (Penobscot) and Examples of Conflation of their Desinences, 1.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
    - Notes on the Southern New England Languages and their Natural History Terms with Penobscot Cognates, 15.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
    - Suprasegmental Phonemes of the Penobscot Dialect of Eastern Abenaki, an Eastern Algonquian Language, 1988; 49.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
    - Tag-Questions in Penobscot, n.d.; 5.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 23)
    - Translation Note, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 23)
    - On Reconstructing a Language Genealogy: The Case of Eastern Algonquian, 1977; 33.0 p.; Warne, Janet L. (Box 23)
    - Wax Cylinder Recordings by Siebert, 1.0 p. (Box 23)
    - Boundary Maintenance in Algonquian: A Linguistic Study of Island Lake, Manitoba, 1971; 50.0 p.; Wolfart, H. Christoph (Box 23)
  - C. Texts (Box 24-25)
    - Abandoned Ocean Islands, 6.0 p. (Box 24)
      Story told by Andrew Dana.
    - Abuleekumoweh, n.d.; 52.0 p. (Box 24)
    - In Indian Tents: Stories Told by Penobscot, Passamaquoddy, and Micmac Indians, 1897; 35.0 p.; Alger, Abby Langdon (Box 24)
      Photocopy excerpts. Grandfather Thunder [incomplete]; Uliske; Story of Walut; Story of Sturgeon; Grandfather Kiawakq; Old Governor John; K'Chi Gess'n, The Northwest Wind; Big Belly; Why the Rabbit's Nose is Split; Story of the Squirrel [incomplete]; Wawbaban, The Northern Lights
    - Alligator, n.d.; 7.0 p. (Box 24)
      Partially translated
    - Ant, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Ant Tells the News, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Arrowhead Fingernails, n.d.; 29.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Bigot Brothers: Writings by one Brother and Notations, 33.0 p. (Box 24)
      Photocopy. Original from the Archives of the Archdiocese of Quebec. Source: Jesuit Mission at Sileny
    - Bumole and the Little Girls, 10.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Bumole, The Air Sprite, n.d.; 16.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Indians' Book, 1907; 4.0 p.; Burlin, Natalie Curtis, 1875-1921 (Box 24)
      Photocopy. Excerpts: The Story of the First Mother; N'ska Wewintuagunul; The Game of Barter; Penobscot Dance-Song; Penobscot Medicine-Song; Dance-Songs; Story of the Moose; Maliseet Love-Song
    - Catechismus Baptismo, n.d.; 60.0 p.
    - Muskrat Root, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Dana, Carol (Box 24)
    - Editorial Notes, 1997; 1.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Elliot Bible, n.d.; 92.0 p. (Box 24)
    - For Now, But Not For Long (Tokec, Katop Qenoq Sipkiw), 1974; 48.0 p. (Box 24)
      Wabnaki Bilingual Education Program
    - Forest Giantess, n.d.; 39.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Ghost Hunter, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Gluskabe and Turtle, 105.0 p. (Box 24)
      Story told by Francis Stanislaus.
    - Gluskabe and the Whale, 2.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Gluskabe Releases the Game Animals, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Great Bear, n.d.; 18.0 p. (Box 24)
    - How Bumole Came to Meddybemps, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Indian Prayer Book: Compiled and Arranged for the Benefit of the Penobscot and Passamaquoddy Tribes, 1834; 30.0 p. (Box 24)
      Photocopy of pamphlet printed by order of the Right Rev. B. Fenwick, Bishop of Boston.
    - Introduction to Texts, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Kino, n.d.; 38.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Kuloskap Tales, n.d.; 18.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Leaner, n.d.; 28.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Legend of the Owl Sacred Pack, 72.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Algonquin Legends of New England, 1884; 22.0 p.; Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1824-1903 (Box 24)
      Photocopy excerpts: Glooskap the Divinity; Amazing Adventures of Master Rabbit; Thunder Stories
    - Catechismos de Baptismo, n.d.; 34.0 p.; Le Sueur, Jean Francois Eustache (Box 24)
      Photocopy of original from the Archives du Seminaire du Quebec
    - Little Pelvis Bone, n.d.; 57.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Gluskabe and his Grandmother, 1.0 p.; Lolar, Louis (Box 24)
    - Lone Light, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Malecite Tales, 1914; 10.0 p.; Mechling, William Hubbs, 1888-1953 (Box 24)
      Photocopy excerpts. Includes: Partridge; Rabbit's Tricks; Laks Goes Salmon-Spearing; How Wolverine was Frozen to Death; How a Man Avenged Himself on His Wife's Paramour; Alaista; The Talking Vagina; The Origin of Corn; The Man who Followed His Wife into Spirit Land
    - Malkohk, The Lazy Lout, n.d.; 26.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Mighty Traveller, n.d.; 8.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Mohawk Chief, n.d.; 7.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Msahtawe, 1995; 5.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Mythological Notes to Tales, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Old Woman of the Forest, and Vocabulary Notes, 4.0 p. (Box 24)
    - Pamoleh of Mt. Katahdin and Translations of Other Texts, 75.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Myths, n.d.; 4.0 folders (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Prayer for Tribal Council Meeting, 1980; 2.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Songs, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Texts, n.d.; 3.0 folders (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Texts and Ethnographic Notes, 29.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Texts Notebooks, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Prayer Card. Sent Ann, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 25)
      In Micmac
    - Raccoon, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Raccoon Races with Rock, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Legends of the Micmacs, 1894; 33.0 p.; Rand, Silas Tertius, 1810-1889 (Box 25)
      Photocopy excerpts. Includes: Glooscap and the Megumoowesoo; The Small Baby and the Big Bird [incomplete]; The Ice Man; Glooscap's Departure from the Land of the Micmacs; A Child Nourished by a Bear; Glooscap Deserted by his Comrades; A Wizard Carries off Glooscap's Housekeeper; The Adventures of Ableegumooch; The Bear and the Woodchuck; Glooscap's Origin; The Beaver Magicians and the Big Fish
    - Red Glow, n.d.; 22.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Seven and Fond of Walking, 19.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Seven Mile Carry Story, n.d.; 5.0 p. (Box 25)
    - European Folk-Tales Among the Penobscot, 1913; 4.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 25)
      Reprint, Journal of American Folklore, vol. 26, no. 99
    - Malecite Tales, 1917; 7.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 25)
      Reprint, Journal of American Folklore, vol. 30, no. 118
    - Penobscot Tales. Some Micmac Tales from Cape Breton Island. Some Naskapi Myths from Little Whale River, 1915; 28.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 25)
      Reprint, Journal of American Folklore, vol. 28, no. 107
    - Wawenock Texts, 1916; 47.0 p.; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 25)
      Annotated photocopy. Original at APS: Frank Speck Papers; Mss.Ms.Coll.126; Series I, Speck, Frank, Wawenock Texts; III (14D13a).
    - Swamp Woman, n.d.; 18.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Tapawas naka Wikohset, n.d.; 12.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Two Indians Go Hunting, 1995; 3.0 p. (Box 25)
      Story told by Arthur Neptune.
    - Unfinished Stories and Fragments, 6.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Water Elves, 1996; 60.0 p. (Box 25)
      Stories told by Andrew Dana, Sebattis Susep John (Chickadee), and Francis Stanislaus
    - Witch Story, n.d.; 32.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Wizards at Gassobias, n.d.; 15.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Wolverine, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Youth and the Youngest Child, 33.0 p. (Box 25)
  - D. Dictionary, 1982-1996 (Box 25-27)
    - Penobscot Dictionary Evolutionary Order, n.d.; 01; 2.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Dictionary Project, 1982; 02; 1.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Organization - Planning - Format, n.d.; 03; 3.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Preface, n.d.; 04; 124.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Introduction, n.d.; 05; 12.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Abbreviations, n.d.; 06; 4.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Dependent Nouns, 07; 53.0 p. (Box 25)
    - English/Penobscot Dependent Nouns, 08; 14.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Dictionary Notes, 1995, n.d.; 09; 50.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Dictionary Pieces, n.d.; 10; 45.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Dictionary Proof Sheets with Reference Card Notes, n.d.; 11; 37.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Language Dictionary First Draft, n.d.; 12; 77.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Sentences, n.d.; 13; 25.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Picture Word List, n.d.; 14; 12.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Pictures for an Elementary Speller, n.d.; 15; 13.0 p. (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Dictionary [1984 version], 16-19; 4.0 folders; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Dictionary, Preface [1984 version], 20; 56.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 25)
    - Penobscot Dictionary [1984 version, annotated], 21-26; 6.0 folders; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 26)
    - Penobscot Indian Dictionary [1986 version], 27-50; 24.0 folders; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 26-27)
      - a, 1986; 27; 98.0 p. (Box 26)
      - a, English to Penobscot, 1986; 28; 16.0 p. (Box 26)
      - α, 1986; 29; 48.0 p. (Box 26)
      - ĉ, ĉĉ, 1986; 30; 19.0 p. (Box 26)
      - e, 1986; 31; 10.0 p. (Box 27)
      - ə, 1986; 32; 7.0 p. (Box 27)
      - h, h w, 1986; 33; 2.0 p. (Box 27)
      - i, 1986; 34; 3.0 p. (Box 27)
      - k, 1986; 35; 61.0 p. (Box 27)
      - kk, 1986; 36; 2.0 p. (Box 27)
      - kk w, 1986; 37; 1.0 p. (Box 27)
      - k w, 1986; 38; 21.0 p. (Box 27)
      - l, 1986; 39; 1.0 p. (Box 27)
      - m, 1986; 40; 45.0 p. (Box 27)
      - n, 1986; 41; 112.0 p. (Box 27)
      - o, 1986; 42; 2.0 p. (Box 27)
      - p, 1986; 43; 75.0 p. (Box 27)
      - pp, 1986; 44; 1.0 p. (Box 27)
      - s, 1986; 45; 31.0 p. (Box 27)
      - ss, 1986; 46; 2.0 p. (Box 27)
      - t, 1986; 47; 25.0 p. (Box 27)
      - tt, 1986; 48; 1.0 p. (Box 27)
      - w, 1986; 49; 63.0 p. (Box 27)
      - y, 1986; 50; 2.0 p. (Box 27)
    - Penobscot Dictionary -- Notecards, n.d.; 51; 3.0 p. (Box 27)
      Photocopies of notecards
    - Penobscot Dictionary, 1996; 52; 500.0 p.; Siebert, Frank T. (Frank Thomas), 1912-1998 (Box 27)
      Bound volume
- IV. Native American Cultures and Languages, 2.0 Linear feet (Box 28-31)
  - American, Making of a New Man (Notes), n.d.; 2.0 p.; Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949 (Box 28)
  - Additions and Corrections to Cuog's Iroquois Dictionary, 2.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Reduplication in Plains Cree, 1982; 2.0 p.; Ahenakew, Freda, 1932-2011; Wolfart, H. Christoph (Box 28)
  - Arapaho Dialects, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Bible Passages in Indian Text, 8.0 p. (Box 28)
    Written 1770-1772 at Sheshequin Plains on the Susquehanna; Indians removed in 1772 to Muskingum River.
  - Bibliographic Reference Cards, n.d.; 23.0 p.
  - Blackfoot Research Notes, Michelson, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Menominee Lexicon, 1975; 3.0 folders; Bloomfield, Leonard, 1887-1949 (Box 28)
    Milwaukee Public Museum Publications in Anthropology and History, no. 3
  - Eskimo Grammar, 1905; 2.0 p.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 28)
    Notecard
  - Nominal *-ka in Proto-Muskogean, 1986; 3.0 p.; Broadwell, George Aaron (Box 28)
  - History of the State of New York, 1609-1664, n.d.; 11.0 p.; Brodhead, John Romeyn, 1814-1873 (Box 28)
    Typed notes
  - Calendar of Council Minutes, 1668-1783, 11.0 p. (Box 28)
    New York State Library Bulletin, no. 58, Albany, 1902
  - Southold Town Records Copied and Explanatory Notes, 1882; 12.0 p.; Case, J. Wickham, (Joseph Wickham) (Box 28)
  - Comparative Vocabulary, n.d.; 14.0 Item(s) (Box 28)
    Note cards featuring comparative vocabulary of varying languages.
  - On the Relationship of Timucua to Muskogean, n.d.; 1.0 p.; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-1989 (Box 28)
  - Cree Vocabulary, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Cultigens in America, n.d.; 20.0 p. (Box 28)
    Includes notes on animals introduced to Americas by Europeans, and assorted linguistic notes.
  - Cultural Notes: Ceremonial Attire, Moccasins, n.d.; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 28)
  - Obviative Intransitives and Point of View in Plains Cree, 1984; 3.0 p.; Dahlstrom, Amy (Box 28)
  - Pronominal Systems in Fox and Cree, 1986; 5.0 p.; Dahlstrom, Amy (Box 28)
  - Delaware Census, 1930, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Dialect Notes, n.d.; 6.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Documents Relating to the Colonial History of the State of New York, n.d.; 42.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Observations on the Language of the Muhhekaneew [Mohegan] Indians, 1787; 8.0 p.; Edwards, Jonathan, 1745-1801 (Box 28)
    Photocopy of pamphlet
  - Epistle Dedicatory, n.d.; 2.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Records of New Amsterdam, 1653-1674, n.d.; 4.0 p.; Fernow, Berthold, 1837-1908 (Box 28)
    Typed excerpts and handwritten notes
  - File Cards, Research Notes, n.d.; 60.0 Item(s) (Box 28)
    Include ethnographic and historical notes
  - First Census of the United States, 1790; U. S. Census of 1890, Report on Indians Taxed and Indians Not Taxed, 11.0 p. (Box 28)
  - Une Analyse Autosegmentale de Quelques Alternances Morphologiques du Cris-Montagnais, n.d.; 2.0 p.; Ford, Alan (Box 28)
  - Indefinite Possessor Prefix in Blackfoot, 1981; 2.0 p.; Frantz, Donald G.; Creighton, Eugene J. (Box 28)
  - Geology and Geography (Box 28)
    Typed notes of E. Lewis, Popular Science Monthly, vol 10, 1877: "Ups and Downs of the Long Island Coast"; Ellen Churchill Semple, Influences of Geographic Environment, 1911
  - Alfred Kiyana's Legend of the Owl Sacred Pack, 1988; 55.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Cheyenne, 1986; 4.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Feature of Fox Narrative Discourse and How to Edit It, 1983; 3.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Fox (Mesquakie) Kinship Terminology, 1992; 11.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
    Photocopy from Cowan (ed.), Papers of the Twenty-Third Algonquian Conference
  - Linguistic Variation in Moraviantown Delaware, 1981; 2.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Observations Regarding Fox (Mesquakie) Phonology, 1981; 26.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
    Proof for Papers of the Twenty-First Algonquian Conference.
  - Pidgin Delaware, 56.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Sketch of Arapaho Linguistic History, 1965; 51.0 p.; Goddard, Ives, 1941- (Box 28)
  - Future Markers in Woods Cree, n.d.; 4.0 p.; Greensmith, J. (Box 28)
  - Notes on the Lingoa Geral or Modern Tupi of the Amazonas, 1872; 3.0 p.; Hartt, Charles Frederick, 1840-1878 (Box 29)
    Transactions for the American Philological Association for 1872. Notes
  - Fox-English Word List; English-Fox Dictionary, n.d.; 182.0 p.; Hewson, John, 1930- (Box 29)
  - Indian Land Rights, 10.0 p. (Box 29)
    Notes
  - Indian Names of the Months, 1856; 1.0 p. (Box 29)
    Photocopied page from New England Historical and Geneological Register, vol. 10
  - Indian Relics and Carvings, 1930; 3.0 p. (Box 29)
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings containing stories of Native American relics and carvings found near Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
  - [Indian Text], 4.0 p. (Box 29)
    Photocopied pages of manuscript written in unidentified language
  - International Phonetic Alphabet, n.d.; 1.0 p.; International Phonetic Association. (Box 29)
    Table from unidentified article by Peter Roach in Phonetics: Phonetic Transcription
  - Itinerary May 2, 1763, 3.0 p. (Box 29)
    Faint, handwritten transcript of unknown historical document with heading "Itinerary May 2, 1763." Mentions travel writing of Lewis Hennepin (1680-1691), and a skirmish involving Iroquois and Miamis.
  - Preterit vs. Preverb ki: Tense, Aspect, and Irreality in Moose Cree, 3.0 p.; James, Deborah (Box 29)
  - Vocabulary of the Language of the Unquachog Indians, 30.0 p.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826 (Box 29)
    Typed copy by Siebert, with written notes
  - Unified Analysis of Relative Clauses and Questions in Rainy River Ojibway, 1981; 3.0 p.; Johns, Alana (Box 29)
  - Enclitic Particles in Fox, 1983; 3.0 p.; Jolley, Catherine A. (Box 29)
  - Kentucky, n.d.; 9.0 p. (Box 29)
  - First Wea Reading Book, 1835, 1970; 25.0 p.; Kerr, Joseph, 1765-1837 (Box 29)
    Photocopy of original at University of Pittsburgh
  - Suppletion in Yuman, 1986; 3.0 p.; Langdon, Margaret, 1926-2005 (Box 29)
  - Cheyenne Deixis, 1983; 2.0 p.; Leman, Wayne (Box 29)
  - Linguistic Notes, n.d.; 4.0 folders (Box 29)
    First folder includes notes on Cree, Delaware, and Munsee.
  - Linguistic Notes - Harrington Journal of American Folklore, n.d.; 14.0 p. (Box 29)
    Includes Martha's Vineyards Records
  - Linguistic Notes - Phonetics, Nature of Languages, Human History, Principles of Comparative Philology, n.d.; 24.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Linguistic Notes - Vocabulary, n.d.; 28.0 p. (Box 29)
    Includes phonological notes (Siebert and Bloomfield); Oklahoma Delaware (from Willie Langbone); assorted vocabulary
  - Linguistic Research - Michigan and Indiana, 14.0 p. (Box 29)
    Series of tables comparing linguistic data of elder individuals living in Michigan and Indiana.
  - Linguistic Society of America - 41st Annual Meeting, 1966; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 29)
    Includes: Zeps, [Central Latvian Long Vowels]; Schramm, Gene M. "Correspondence of Distinctive Oppositions in Distantly Related Languages"; Teeter, Karl V. "Evolution of the Algic Verbal System"; Langacker, Ronald W. "French Possessives"; Kazazis, Kostas. "On the Phonology of Palatalized Consonantism in Modern Greek"; Keyser, S. Jay. "Linguistic Basis of English Prosody"; Bender, Byron C. "Toward a Systematic Phonemicization of Marshallese"
  - Lord's Prayer, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Mahican, n.d.; 26.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Manuscript Sources, n.d.; 18.0 p. (Box 29)
    Manuscripts in Pennsylvania Historical Society; typed notes from Andrews and Davenport, "Guide to the Manuscript Materials for the History of the U.S. to 1783, in the British Museum, in the Minor London Archives, and in the Libraries of Oxford and Cambridge", 1908; Public Record Office, London
  - Obviatif en Montagnais, 1982; 5.0 p.; Martin, Pierre, 1947- (Box 29)
    La Linguistique, vol. 18. In French
  - Longueur des Voyelles en Cris, 1978; 23.0 p.; Martin, Pierre, 1947- et al (Box 29)
    Reprint. In French
  - Massachusetts Archives List, n.d.; 20.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Background and Explanatory Description for this Mahican Dictionary, 1984-1986; 29.0 p.; Masthay, Carl (Box 29)
  - I Love You in About 310 Languages, 1986; 12.0 p.; Masthay, Carl (Box 29)
  - Schmick's Mahican Manuscript Transcribed and Rearranged by English Translation, 1982; 140.0 p.; Masthay, Carl (Box 29)
  - Minutes of the Executive Council of the Province of New York, 1668-1673, n.d.; 3.0 Item(s) (Box 29)
    Handwritten notes
  - Miscellaneous. Foods, Winsor, Mooney, Spofford, Johnson, Zeisberger, Loskiel, Heckewelder, etc., n.d.; 17.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Mohegan-Pequot Vocabulary, n.d.; 9.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Montauk Vocabulary, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 29)
    From Silas Wood
  - Mortuary Customs, n.d.; 33.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Diminutive Syntax, 1986; 4.0 p.; Munro, Pamela (Box 29)
  - Munsee, n.d.; 3.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Mythological Motifs: Brief Mythological Notes, n.d.; 4.0 p. (Box 29)
  - Narragansett Vocabulary, 1770-1784, n.d.; 7.0 p. (Box 30)
    Copies of unknown source; typed and handwritten notes
  - Native American Cartographers, n.d.; 1.0 p. (Box 30)
    Short bibliography
  - Calendar of Historical Manuscripts in the Office of the Secretary of State, Albany, New York, 1865; 10.0 p.; O’Callaghan, E. B., (Edmund Bailey), 1797-1880 (Box 30)
    Typed excerpts and notes
  - Documentary History of the State of New York, 1850; 32.0 p.; O’Callaghan, E. B., (Edmund Bailey), 1797-1880 (Box 30)
  - Grammar of Delaware: Semantics, Morpho-Syntax, Lexicon, Phonology, 1972; 234.0 p.; Pearson, Bruce L., b. 1932 (Box 30)
    Copy of dissertation from University of California, Berkeley
  - Savannah and Shawnee: The End of a Microcontroversy, 1987; 11.0 p.; Pearson, Bruce L., b. 1932 (Box 30)
    International Journal of American Linguistics, vol. 53
  - Pequot Dictionary, n.d.; 9.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Pequot Indian Vocabulary, 1756-1762; 4.0 p. (Box 30)
    Copies of unknown source
  - Account of Several Nations of Southern Indians, 1768; 1.0 p.; Potter, Elam, 1742-1794 (Box 30)
    Photocopy from Collections of the Massachusetts Historical Society, vol. 10
  - Publications of the Bureau of American Ethnology, 1964; 11.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Quapaw and Cherokee - Linguistic Notes, 1963; 61.0 p. (Box 30)
  - Quapaw Vocabulary, 1982; 29.0 p.; Rankin, Robert Louis, 1939- (Box 30)
    Photocopy, Kansas Working Papers in Linguistics, vol. 7
  - Unmaking of Quapaw Phonology: A Study of Language Death, 1978; 8.0 p.; Rankin, Robert Louis, 1939- (Box 30)